# Mike Wright

### Full Stack Developer

3423 East Monterosa Street Phoenix, AZ 85018 (623) 229-4457 mike.wright@itsallwater.net

### **SUMMARY**

Mike is a native of Phoenix. A graduate from Arizona State University, he is currently a full-time remote Senior Software Developer with Zumasys. He has over ten years of experience developing applications in PickBASIC, NoSQL, ASP.NET, .NET Core, C#, VB.NET, PowerBI, Microsoft SQL, SSIS, SSRS, JavaScript, JQuery, Vue.js, CSS and HTML.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Zumasys, San Clemente, CA -** *Senior Software Developer* 

OCTOBER 2018 - CURRENT

- Executed custom development projects for various Zumasys clients, including HTML/CSS/JavaScript/Vue Web applications, VB.NET Windows applications, Power BI reporting, API development and backend work in jBASE, D3 and UniVerse. Some of those projects were solo efforts, others were tandems and the remaining were multi-person teams.
- Contributed to internal development efforts including a home-grown ticketing system web application on .NET Core 2.2.
- Regularly traveled for on-site visits with client base to discuss ongoing and prospective projects and perform technical work. Otherwise, position was remote from a home office in Phoenix, AZ.

**Equiant Financial Services Inc., Scottsdale, AZ** - Vice President of IT

JUNE 2017 - AUGUST 2018

- Grew team to one manager of software development, two software architects, six developers, two network/systems engineer and two interns.
- Oversaw all development work for the D3 system, ASP.NET/C# web applications and Microsoft SQL Report Server.
- Managed migration from private cloud provider to Microsoft Azure.
- Instituted Jira Cloud and implemented the Agile Scrum development methodology.
- Added HIPAA to compliance audits while maintaining PCI DSS 3.2 Level 1 and SSAE-18 SOC 1 Type 2.

### **Equiant Financial Services Inc., Scottsdale, AZ** - Director of IT

JANUARY 2016 - MAY 2017

- Managed a team of five full-time developers, one network/systems engineer and three interns.
- Oversaw all development work for the D3 system, ASP.NET/C# web applications and Microsoft SQL Report Server.
- Led migration from Microsoft SQL 2008 to 2014.
- Successfully ran the conversion from a local Microsoft Exchange server to Office 365.
- Organized PCI DSS 3.2 Level 1 and SSAE-16 SOC 1 Type 2 audits.

## **Equiant Financial Services Inc., Scottsdale, AZ** - Manager of Web Dev.

JUNE 2013 - DECEMBER 2015

- Managed a team of three interns and one full-time web developer.
- Integrated Report Server's Schedule & Subscription services into the main web portal.
- Led team in developing new pages to allow for onboarding of new accounts through the web portal.
- Also led team in developing a file loading process available through the web portal, to allow for bulk processing directly by the customer base.

# **Equiant Financial Services Inc., Scottsdale, AZ** - Senior Web Developer

SEPTEMBER 2011 - JUNE 2013

- Updated the Equiant corporate site with a responsive design.
- Integrated ShoreTel IVR with C# web services to provide a new consumer facing phone system.
- Oversaw data migration from Pick to Microsoft SQL for report generation via Reporting Services. Utilized the Reporting Services API to allow users to interact with reports within the main web portal in a custom user control.

### Equiant Financial Services Inc., Scottsdale, AZ -

Programmer/Analyst

FEBRUARY 2008 - SEPTEMBER 2011

- Worked extensively on the Pick back-end subroutines for the Equiant website and the ColdFusion front-end. Created queries and handled data flow, both into and out of Pick.
- Led the transition from old ColdFusion websites to new ASP.NET websites
  with C# integration using BlueFinity's mv.NET to connect with Pick. Rewrote back-end subroutines in Pick to provide data more efficiently to the
  new sites and web services.

# **Equiant Financial Services Inc., Scottsdale, AZ** - Pgmr./Analyst Intern

MAY 2005 - FEBRUARY 2008

- Developed new tools and reports for in-house and client use.
- Optimized several processes to run automatically, including: FedEx shipment tracking, currency wiring, Bankruptcy detection & notification (via LexisNexis).
- Managed loan and billing statement, letter, and membership card generation and mailing (via interfaces with BestBill and Nordis Direct).

### **EDUCATION**

**Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ** - *B.S., Computer Science* AUGUST 2003 - DECEMBER 2007